Well. of course you know
Justin Foley is a drug addict?
Well. you need to...
for where we're going.
What?
What's going on?
Yeah.
You tell me.
- You went through my fucking shit?
- Let's skip the righteous anger
and fast forward to you explaining
why you have an Oxy prescription
- in the name of Bryce Walker.
- Fuck.
Okay. Look. Clay.
- Are you using again?
- No!
- I don't believe you.
- I'm... I'm not!
Jesus. Clay. I swear.
You told me that the last time
you saw Bryce was at the end of summer.
This prescription is from a month ago.
You guys stayed in contact.
He sold these to you. didn't he?
You've got it all wrong.
Then explain it to me.
Where did you find the pills?
At the Chatham house.
Bryce's funeral.
- Don't lie to me.
- I'm not! Dude. you...
You saw me.
Upstairs. in the hallway. Remember?
I told you I was looking for the bathroom.
I had just taken the Oxy
from Bryce's bathroom. that's...
That's why I was acting so weird.
but I'm telling you.
it was just that once.
It was just that day.
Bryce was dead.
and I was all fucked up.
And I just went to look
for a place to chill.
and suddenly. I was in Bryce's room and...
it was fucking with my head.
I just felt empty and messed up and...
just alone.
- So. it was just one time?
- Yeah.
I fucked up.
I'm sorry. I'm really...
I'm really sorry.
Just please...
don't tell your folks.
Because life with an addict
means you never know what to believe.
You're always waiting
for the next bad news.
What happened?
Clay. honey. sit down.
I don't want to sit down.
You've officially been named
a person of interest
by the Sheriff.
He held a press conference
this morning.
- A press conference?
- What does that mean?
"A person of interest?"
What the fuck is that?
Character assassination is what it is.
- It's a tactic.
- It means nothing legally.
Doesn't feel like nothing.
- Feels like they're about to arrest me!
- They can't.
They don't have enough.
So they try to put public pressure on you.
They don't have the evidence
to call you a suspect.
but they want you scared.
- Well done. then.
- Maybe it's best
- if you boys stay home from school today.
- No.
No way. We're not doing that.
- Clay...
- You can stay home.
No. of course not.
I've got your back. That's what we do.
Let's get a coffee on the way and talk.
And then the bad news gets worse.
And it feels like the world is closing in.
Taken?
- Knock yourself out.
- Yeah. I should hope not.
Coffee's supposed to do the opposite
of that. right?
No school today?
It starts in half an hour.
Yeah. I'm surprised you're going.
I'm sorry?
After the police named you
a person of interest
in Bryce Walker's murder.
How does that feel?
What the...
- Who are you?
- Austin James.
I write for The Evergreen County Register.
Just want to chat about the case.
Hey. get the fuck out.
Just enjoying a cup of coffee.
All right. then we'll get the fuck out.
If you come in here again. I'll see to it
that your coffee is pissed in.
- Thanks for the save.
- Yeah. What a dick.
And here's the thing.
When they made Clay a person of interest
the searchlight shone on Justin. as well.
So. it was only a matter of time...
You need a spot?
...until his secrets came out.
Yeah. not from you.
Man. your boy Clay is in some shit.
Hey. Clay in shit.
He should change his name to shit.
- Dude. you are so fucking stupid.
- You feeling all right?
You look kinda sick.
Did your boy find your stash?
What the fuck do you know about it?
I pay attention.
Kind of made me wonder...
what if Brycey found out
you were using again.
so you and Shit took him out?
You know. Clay thinks you did it.
He's just desperate.
It's not like he's got anything.
I think he's got something.
I think he knows exactly...
why you did it.
So either two things
could have happened:
you did do it...
or maybe Clay and I did.
Maybe you're next.
Clay felt every set of eyes on him.
desperately searching for a way out.
desperately hoping
the answer wasn't Justin.
Ignore the chatter.
It's pretty loud.
Well. don't talk back.
- You mean don't defend myself?
- It doesn't matter what you say.
it matters how you seem.
And you seem angry.
Guilty people get angry.
Maybe people who are falsely accused
get more angry.
But you're still not sure
which one I am. right?
Oh.
and your precious Bryce was doing Oxy.
What makes you think that?
Because Justin stole some
from his room after the funeral.
Is that what Justin told you?
And you believe him?
I believe it of Bryce.
I should've told him everything I knew.
But...
But he was right.
I hadn't made my mind up yet.
And your press conference worked
on me.
Did Bryce ever deal Oxy?
No. Bryce did not deal Oxy.
How can you be so sure?
Uh. 'cause I tried to buy some from him
and he flat-out refused.
Why would you need it?
Sprained hamstring from lifting.
I wanted something
to push through the pain.
but he wouldn't give it to me.
He said that shit was too addictive.
That's oddly considerate.
Yeah. I thought so.
So. why do you want to know
if Bryce dealt Oxy?
Um. you know. um...
I'm trying to figure out
who may have killed him.
- It wasn't me.
- Where does the Oxy come in?
I don't know.
Gentlemen. Solve. please.
But while everyone
was looking at Clay.
I was thinking about Justin.
Hey.
- I suck. I've been totally avoiding you.
- I don't blame you.
Alex really fucked shit up for you.
Using me.
So. transitively.
I fucked shit up for you.
Math.
It's not your fault.
It fucking feels like it.
All I do is mess up your life.
I'm the hypocrite.
not you.
Jess. I...
I don't want this to be over.
I don't either.
Okay. So. maybe we just...
go back on the down-low
till all this settles?
No.
No. I'm supposed to be
living my truth. right?
Well. the truth is
that I love your lame ass. Justin Foley.
People are gonna talk about us.
People always talk about us.
Fuck 'em.
- Fuck 'em.
- Fuck!
No way. No. if Justin were using.
he would've been caught. We were tested.
Well. he told me he only used once
a few weeks ago.
Would that have been
after you got tested?
Maybe he got lucky
and the timing worked out. I don't know.
Or maybe you knew he was using
and you helped him?
No. No way. I won't put up
with that shit. okay? We play clean.
He's been doing well. Clay.
Football's been good for him.
you know it has. He's healthy.
Yeah. I thought he was.
- I hoped...
- He's healthy. okay?
I mean. that's the whole reason
I got him to play last summer.
Zach. I don't need
a fucking lecture. all right?
Dude. that shit will rot your insides.
Have you seen what it does to a penny?
Have you seen
what I've done to my insides?
So. summer school's over. We start
two days next week. Perfect timing.
- Except I have no desire to play again.
- Dude. we need you. and you need football.
I'm not letting this go. man.
Zach Dempsey always gets the yes.
Zach Dempsey has gotten the yes
exactly once.
Fuck off!
- I'm just... I'm not that guy anymore.
- You're not what guy?
Not the guy that needs
to rediscover his competitive fire?
Not the guy who needs brotherhood
and fellowship in his life?
Not the guy who needs to rebuild
his once athletic body?
Correct. I'm none of those guys.
- Dude!
- Dude.
Dude.
What the hell?
Dude!
Are you throwing grapes
all over my bed?
Well. it's the international semi-finals
for the Olympic-qualifying
Grape Throwing Competition.
What are you even doing here?
I'm not leaving until Justin agrees
to do football this year.
He thinks it'd be good for me.
I mean. it probably would be. wouldn't it?
He agrees with me.
Holy shit. Clay actually agrees with me!
Hey. stop fucking throwing grapes
at my bed. okay?
Hey. that's not funny!
Go outside and play! Hey! What the...
Justin! What the fuck?
- All right.
You're cleaning this up!
- Uh-huh.
- Nope!
Justin hoped football would help him
find himself again.
Up!
Get the knees up!
Heels straight up under the body! Up!
Up!
Down! Come on. Don't stop. Come on.
Push-ups. Let's go. don't stop.
Two laps. let's go. Go!
Go!
Foley. come on. Get moving. man.
You quit out here. you quit in a game.
Yeah. maybe I should just quit now
and save everyone the trouble.
Yeah. you're right. Just walk away.
You're not even worth it.
- You want me to go?
- You got a reason to stay?
I can't give it to you.
You gotta find that for yourself.
Okay. I'll go.
Yeah. go back
to what you were doing before.
Go do some drugs. Like white trash do.
Hey. what the fuck did you just say to me?
Hey. back off
and watch that language. That's a mile.
- You can't talk to me like that.
- Yeah. you're right.
I got no idea where you come from.
Hey. where'd you score? Huh?
Down on Fifth?
Down by the docks?
Yeah. Yeah. I don't know you.
All I know is you go back there.
you ain't getting back out again.
So. you run that track. two miles.
or you just run the hell out of here.
- Don't even look back.
- How's it two miles already?
You want three?
Go.
Go!
The way back isn't ever easy.
You can't eliminate student council
funding for the football team.
You have plenty of funding
from the district.
You have more funding than the drama
and music programs put together.
We have more guys involved
than music and drama put together.
We have four teams.
I promised I would do everything I could
to eradicate jock culture.
But you can't say
that jock culture is this or that.
there isn't just one culture.
And...
I mean. we're changing things around here.
Male athletic programs
not only protect athletes
who commit sexual assault.
they foster a culture
of violence and aggression
that creates rapists every day.
Jess...
some guys do shit.
Athletes and non-athletes.
But for lots of guys.
football's their only shot
at a college scholarship.
Football. athletics.
for some people they're a lifeline.
Like who?
Like me.
Look. I didn't want
to come back to football. but...
once I did. it...
it got me out of bed in the morning
and it...
got me back in myself and shit that...
I feel like myself for the first time...
in a really long time.
Look.
cut our funding or don't.
In the end. you're not gonna win.
Because we're not gonna give up.
He's passed every drug test.
hasn't missed a practice.
He's in good shape.
I want to believe that.
So. do.
Some wanted to believe
the best of Justin.
Some never could.
You need to tell Jess
that you're using again.
Did Clay tell you that?
It's true. isn't it?
- Did Clay tell you?
- No. but you are.
Using.
What the fuck does it matter to you?
You're just looking for another reason
to be pissed at me?
- To fuck things up between me and Jess?
- Yeah and no.
I do think
that you're a worthless piece of shit
that doesn't deserve her. but...
she seems to love you
for whatever reason.
But you can't deal with that?
I've been dealing with it
for two years now. asshole.
while you've been destroying her life.
- When are you gonna fucking quit?
- When are you?
She deserves the truth.
While Justin started to spiral...
Clay took refuge
in one of the few friends he had left.
Hey.
Uh... what's up?
Just checking on you.
You okay?
Shouldn't I be asking you?
You saw the news?
Yeah. I kinda think everyone did.
For what it's worth.
you've always been interesting to me.
As a person.
That was supposed to be a joke.
Maybe it's not a time for jokes.
Maybe I'm not good at jokes. Um...
Little bit of both. but thanks for trying.
Hey. would it be stupid if I...
gave you some advice?
About something I know about?
Um...
No. not...
Not stupid. What's up?
When people stare at you and talk...
or they don't stare but you can tell
that they want to. just...
just remember that you know who you are.
and they don't.
Right.
Thanks. Ty.
Clay knew who he was...
but he wasn't sure
he knew who Justin was anymore.
And without Justin. it felt to him
like Clay Jensen versus the world.
No. thank you.
And he was so tired of that feeling.
Hot off the press.
Issue 140. Sweet.
Wait. hold on.
We finally find out
if Percy forgives Astrid
for leaving him for dead on Rykon 7.
and all you've got is "sweet?"
I thought maybe we could read it together.
No. it's okay. I'll... I'm just gonna...
I'll pick it up later.
You're still angry with me.
I was never angry with you.
Are you sure
you know what anger feels like?
I'm not angry.
My. uh...
friend...
Hannah.
I told you about her?
Not much.
Well...
she. uh...
She killed herself.
A year ago today.
Sweet Jesus. I'm...
I'm so sorry.
No. it's okay. It's just. it's...
It's been on my mind.
I'm sure.
Do you want to talk about it?
No. I don't.
Okay.
Well. would you like me to sit with you?
What is this?
That we're doing?
Being friends?
Okay. yeah. but...
you started this friendship. not me.
I didn't even want any more friends.
The ones I have are already a whole lot.
so...
We both have...
complicated lives.
I thought maybe we could be
something simple for each other.
And not have to talk about everything.
And what if nothing's simple?
What if everything's complicated?
What do we do then?
I don't know. exactly.
Hey. man. Mind if we join you?
No. not at all.
This healthy school lunch thing
is the worst.
- Hey. my mom could bag you a lunch.
- Are you eating three sandwiches?
I'm growing.
God. I hope not.
You're like a fucking giant.
Clay. man. we should hang out more.
Yeah.
No. we totally should.
Um...
you know I didn't kill Bryce. right?
Oh. yeah. totally.
We don't hang out with murderers.
only the dispossessed.
I don't know what that word means.
but right on.
Clay had people who believed him.
I decided I was one of those people.
Clay!
- What is it?
- Justin was lying to you.
Why do you say that?
He's told you he stole a bottle
after the funeral? Just a one-off?
Yeah. a one-time relapse.
He says he found the pills
in Bryce's bedroom during the wake.
He's lying.
After the police found Bryce's
steroid stash at the crime scene.
they swept his room clean.
Wait. what?
Shit!
Hey. there.
Jess. not now.
What? We're public.
Yeah. and it feels like
you're making a big show out of it.
What the hell does that mean?
It means that it doesn't feel like
it's about us.
it feels like it's about you.
It's not! What's going on with you?
Just stop using me
to make a fucking point!
I'm not!
The only point I'm making is that
I love you and that's all that matters.
Okay. well. you...
you shouldn't love me. You shouldn't.
What? Why not?
Because I'm fucking bad for you!
Hey. what are you saying right now?
Talk to me. What's going on?
I cheated on you.
- What?
- I said I cheated on you!
I don't believe you.
Okay. well. it's true. You should.
When?
- When did this happen?
- Homecoming night.
You tried to call me. That's where I was.
I was with some other girl.
Who?
Jess. it doesn't matter.
You just shouldn't be with me. okay?
It's fucking over.
The Oxy that you stole
from Bryce's room.
where exactly did you find it?
It was. um...
It was in his medicine cabinet.
In the bathroom.
Lies are harder to remember
than the truth. aren't they?
I cleaned that bathroom out myself.
You didn't find anything.
Was he selling?
And did you owe him money?
Why would I kill Bryce
after he saved my fucking life?
There you go.
- Extra hot. please.
- Yeah.
I like it when it burns.
What the fuck are you doing here?
I just got out of County.
I had four long months
to think about all the money you owe me.
I don't owe you shit.
Either you pay me or you work.
No. I'm not doing that.
Then pay me.
Can we not do this here?
You meet me out back in five.
Rookie fucking mistake.
Did you really think my customers
wouldn't notice you skimming off the top?
- Fuck. Seth.
- You little junkie shit!
- Let me explain.
- No. shut up!
I don't want to hear any
of your bullshit excuses. Justin!
I tried to give you a chance
to work off your debt.
Now I just want my fucking money.
- All right.
- I want 2.000.
For what you owe and what you stole.
And I want it tomorrow.
- I can't get it to you that fast. man.
- No?
Then maybe you're gonna have to ask
your new rich family for help.
Or maybe I'll ask them myself.
- No. I'll do it. I'll take care of it.
- Yeah. you will.
Fuck...
Thank you.
Yeah.
You okay?
My lawyer...
They made it all go away.
I mean. they only had you
for a misdemeanor anyway.
because apparently.
you smoked it all
before they got there.
They didn't call your mom?
They tried. She's long gone.
Yeah. right. You're with the Jensens now.
- The cops didn't know that.
- Right. Right. right.
Can you...
Could you give me a ride home?
Yeah. man. Of course.
Hey. listen. The deputy told my lawyer
that Seth is back in town.
Are you caught up with him?
- Justin...
- I...
I can handle it. Okay?
Okay.
But you know I'm here for you. right?
For anything.
- Yeah. I know.
- Okay.
I'm your brother forever. no matter what.
He couldn't call the Jensens.
He had no one else.
And. in a way. neither did Bryce.
So. they had each other.
Who the fuck is Abercrombie?
He's my friend.
- I know you from somewhere?
- No. you don't.
He's got the money.
Can we just get this done with already?
Okay. let's see it.
This is 5.000.
To cover Justin's debt.
and to make sure that you leave him alone.
for good.
And what are you gonna do if I don't?
Then I guess you're gonna have to find out
how good of a friend I really am.
You're that rapist kid. aren't you?
I thought I recognized you.
That is some fucked-up shit you did.
Yep. that's me.
Fucked up.
And my life is pretty fucked up. too.
Which means I have no problem
dedicating whatever's left of it
to ruining yours.
So...
what's it gonna be?
Can I ask you a question?
Are you just smoking it
or are you shooting it. too?
- Yeah. both.
- Fuck! Justin...
That shit will kill you dead. One shot
you get something that's too strong
- or fucking fentanyl or some shit...
- What. are you gonna teach me now?
No. No. of course not.
But I don't want you to die.
You take this shit?
I don't. no.
Makes me puke like a fire hose.
- Fire hoses don't puke per se.
- Shut the fuck up.
I got it when I twisted my ankle.
Take that shit instead. okay?
Taper off it if you can.
Don't fucking die.
Bryce had my back.
If it wasn't for him. Seth...
He would've blown my brains out.
Did you ever see him again?
Bryce?
It was just a one-time thing.
I tried to avoid him
until the Homecoming game.
Just. I couldn't...
I couldn't face him.
So. you have no idea how he died?
Seth...
sent me a text
on the day they found his body.
Jesus.
I didn't kill Bryce.
But I think that
I might be the reason he is dead.
So. you really believe
that Seth killed Bryce?
I don't know. Maybe.
It could be that he... he did.
It could be that...
we make the cops think that he did.
Either way. I know where to start.
- All right. we gotta be quick.
- Can we expect him back soon?
I don't know. Ani.
He doesn't exactly keep banker's hours.
Somebody's been shopping.
Yeah. with Bryce's money.
I'm guessing.
So. let's find proof.
Anything that links Seth to Bryce.
Holy shit! Guys.
This is Bryce's watch.
Which means they met up again.
Maybe Bryce gave it to him
when Seth came back for more.
Or he took it.
Off of Bryce's body after he killed him.
- We have to go to the cops.
- We...
What the fuck are you doing here?
We know what you did to Bryce Walker.
We're calling the cops.
- No. Clay. don't!
- The fuck you talking about?
Justin told me how Bryce paid
you off so you'd leave him alone.
- Oh. he did now?
- Clay. stop!
And you went back to Bryce. right?
For more money. but he refused
so you taught him a lesson.
And what lesson was that?
You killed him.
- You don't know shit.
- Then why do you have his watch?
Is that what you think?
Shut the fuck up. Seth.
I had no idea
the watch belonged to the dead kid.
Junkie here gave it to me
for product.
He's a fucking liar!
You can live in a fancy house.
but you're still a fucking junkie.
- Just like your whore mama.
- Fuck you!
- Justin!
- Get the fuck back.
Whoa! Justin!
Go! Go!
Go!
Fuck!
So. Justin was the criminal
in the family.
but Clay was the one
about to be accused of a crime.
Legally. it should have no bearing
on the adoption proceedings.
but Clay's over 18 now.
and if any adult living in the household
has been convicted of a felony...
the adoption will be denied.
So. what do we do?
For now. we wait.
They won't recommend your case
to a judge until...
until they have some clarity
on Clay's situation.
Okay.
Justin?
You always have a home here.
no matter what.
Okay?
Yeah.
Yeah. I know.
You boys get some sleep.
- I'm sorry.
- For what?
For fucking what?
I mean. you didn't do anything.
It's not your fault.
You have nothing to be sorry for.
I love you. man.
Yeah. me too.
I have to take a shit.
When you live with an addict.
everything starts looking suspicious.
Like the one time Justin decides
to close the door to do his business.
Justin!
- Shut the fucking door!
- What're you doing?
What the fuck does it look like?
You've been lying to me.
You've been getting high this whole time!
No.
No. I don't... I don't get high anymore.
I get by. I maintain. I fucking...
I fucking survive!
Seth was telling the truth
- about the watch. wasn't he?
- I didn't kill Bryce!
Then help me believe you!
Tell me how you ended up with his watch.
No more lies!
Okay.
No more lies.
He told Clay
it was actually the watch
he had taken the day of the funeral.
but he had taken much more from Bryce
before that.
Justin!
Dude. Justin. wake the fuck up!
Come on. man!
What the fuck?
Dude. I've been waiting outside
for ten minutes.
The team breakfast? It's game day.
Come on. dude. Let's go.
Shit.
Clean clothes. come on. let's go.
Is this...
Is this clean?
All right. everyone listen up.
Listen up in the back. all right?
This is the start of league play
for the year.
Yeah!
Per state rules. players will be
drug tested at three random times.
Tonight. gentlemen.
is one of those random times.
So. when we get to the field house
for East County.
we will go directly
into the visitor locker room.
state guys will supervise the testing.
all right?
Can we give sperm
instead of piss?
'Cause I like to yank one off
before the game.
Stay classy. Monty. all right?
- Your captain's got a few words.
- Yeah!
- Let's go!
- Yeah. get it.
Boys.
tonight. we show them
what kind of team we are.
from the fucking piss test
to the real test out on the field.
- Yes!
- Let's show them!
I am so proud
of every single one of you!
The team had made Justin feel
like he belonged again.
Tigers!
Until that night.
- Yeah!
- He watched Monty.
Zach and Luke.
how it all seemed so easy for them.
And he felt more and more lost.
Come on! Yeah!
Christ!
Foley. get in there!
Sports had always been the cure
for Justin.
the thing that made him feel alive.
But on the field that night...
he felt more alone than ever.
Go. go. go!
- Damn it!
- Shit!
Damn it!
Whatever you think is best.
Switch them if you want.
Hey. Foley. Foley. what the hell?
Taylor was gonna pick the guy up
over the middle.
No. man coverage. dude.
That means cover your man!
- Talk to fucking Taylor!
- Hey. don't you...
- Don't you walk away from me.
- What?
What do you want me to say?
"I messed up. Coach."
That's what I want you to say.
"I messed up.
I'll get it right next time."
- Whatever.
- Okay. yeah. Whatever.
Don't give me whatever.
"Whatever" is a piece of shit word.
Don't be a piece of shit.
Okay.
Hey. hey.
Justin.
Justin. hey. look at me. Look at me.
Look. listen to me.
Did you make a coverage
- on that last down?
- No.
No. sir.
That's all I want from you.
- What. like an apology?
- No. no apology. Accountability.
Look. we owe that to each other.
We do our best. We fuck up. man.
We get better and we learn.
You get me?
Yes. sir.
Okay.
We fuck up.
We get better.
But sometimes it's not enough.
Sometimes we fuck up again and again.
Hey. man. You good?
I fucking suck tonight.
Second half. Come back.
Dude...
I...
I'm not gonna pass this drug test.
- Man. Justin...
- I know.
You were right. man.
About playing again. It... It's been...
I mean. it's been good for me.
I'm just gonna fuck it up
because I fuck up everything.
Man. I can't...
I can't help you.
I know. I...
I just wanted you to be
the first person I told.
Foley! Nickel!
Come on. get in there.
- I got you.
- What?
- How?
I made a switch.
- How'd you get around...
- Just shut the fuck up!
You're clean. okay?
Hey.
I heard
you got your dicks fed to you tonight.
Yeah. we sucked.
You're not gonna get a win this year.
Till we play Hillcrest.
Yeah.
Ah. shit.
Fuck. man.
How did we get like this. you and me?
You raped my girlfriend.
He gave you the drugs
so he could control you.
Same reason he ever gave you anything.
No. this was different. He...
was different.
- He's a user. Justin. Always was.
- If anything. I was using him.
But you didn't kill him?
No.
But you weren't with Jessica that night?
Where were you?
After the Homecoming game. I...
I needed to get fucked up. so I did.
Where'd you go?
Down by the docks.
How do I know I can believe you?
Why did you go to Bryce for help?
Instead of me?
Come on. man.
You can figure that one out.
You detoxed me once. remember?
How do we get you clean now?
We tell your parents.
They send me away.
They wouldn't.
To a treatment center
or a rehab. or some bullshit like that.
Maybe it works. maybe it doesn't.
Maybe I just...
get the hell out of here
and spare everyone the trouble.
You... you don't want to do that.
though. right?
I really...
really don't.
You all made Clay
a person of interest.
Isolated. Alone in the world.
Except for Justin.
Just so you know...
I'd do anything for you.
Anything.
Same.
They had a bond stronger than blood.
Even if the blood was Bryce Walker's.
Hi. Mrs. Baker.
Yeah. I'm sorry I didn't call you back.
I just...
Justin said
he'd do anything for Clay.
Yes.
We should talk.
All right. Yeah. I'll see you then.
And that was
about to get complicated.
Shit!
For help finding crisis resources.
visit 13reasonswhy.info.
Well done. Ed. well done.